

SOUMYA PRAKASH DUTTA

I am a professional Mechanical Design Engineer with 3 years of experience of Solid modelling, Finite element analysis and Simulation. Seeking to leverage my professional expertise and experience into in a company which specializes in CAD/CAE work which will allow me to learn more and expand my capabilities into new areas as well help this as organization grow collectively.

Education

2018 | Osmania University, Hyderabad

Master's in Mechanical Engineering Specializing in Design For Manufacture

2015 | SOA University, Bhubaneswar

Bachelor's in Mechanical Engineering

Contact

- +91-7008469325
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/so umya-prakash-dutta-a19896b7/
- Acharya Vihar, Bhubaneshwar, Odisha. 751013

Work Experience

CSIR-IMMT Bhubaneswar | Feb 2021 - present **Project Associate**

 Design and modelling of Laboratory Equipments and devices according to required experimentation and conditions.

CSIR-CSIO Chandigarh | Dec 2018 - March 2020 **Project Assistant**

- Design and modelling of Pressure Vessels for cold chamber storage.
- Engineering calculations, specifications and drawings associated with refrigeration systems.
- CFD Analysis of Refrigeration System Components.

Ordnance Factory Medak | Feb 2017 - Jan 2018 **Graduate Intern**

- Modelling and drafting of welding fixtures and assembly fixtures.
- FEA Structural Analysis, Static and structural analysis,
- Suspension System Analysis of Tracked Vehicle.

Skills

- CAD Soildworks, Creo
- CFD Ansys Fluent
- Fixture Design
- Refrigeration & HVAC
- GD & T
- Python Scripting



Trainings & Workshops

- "The Aerotrix Super Challenge to construct a RC Aircraft" Organized by Aerotrix, IIST Trivandrum in the year 2013.
- Certified CATIA V5 from Dassault Systems in the year 2018.
- Certified Hypermesh from DesignTech in the year 2018.
- Certified AUTOCAD from CIPET in the year 2013.

SOUMYA PRAKASH DUTTA

Dear HR Manager

Your company Capegemini recently advertised on it's website for a Mechanical Design Engineer role. After reading the job description I am confident that I would be a perfect fit for your position as my skills, ability and future potential precisely match your requirements.

Without wishing to sound boastful I feel that I come to you with a background that is unique and distinctive from other applicants. I have all of the competencies required to do the job well, in particular I want to highlight my ability to create designs and analyze them independently. My other core strengths include, but are not limited to the following:

- ·Solid modelling, Assembling, Detailing, simulation, value engineering, GD & T, sketching of new conceptual design, material selection.
- ·Finite element analysis using Ansys and Hypermesh.
- ·Being able to work in an environment of change, multiple deadlines.
- ·Scheduling workloads to meet priorities and targets.

For additional information about my capabilities please view my attached resume.

I would welcome the chance of an interview, where we would be able to discuss in greater detail the value and strength I can bring to your already successful company.

I thank you very much for your time and I eagerly look forward to hearing from you.

Soumya Prakash Dutta